ATCHI REDDY D V

IT SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

SUMMARY

Having experience as Azure Data Engineer with close to 7.3 years of designing, developing, and maintaining data solutions on on-premises & the Azure platform. Proficient in managing and scaling Azure data services, ensuring data accuracy and security, and developing tools to optimize performance. Experienced in data modeling and data warehousing concepts, with a strong background in MSBI (SSIS, SSRS, SSAS) development using SQL Server versions 2008, 2012, 2014, and 2016.

CONTACT

- +91-6364039896
- Atchi.reddy055@gmail.com
- Bengaluru, India 560068

SKILLS

- Data Processing with PySpark
- Experience with Databricks
- Data Pipeline Development in Azure
- Infrastructure as Code Expertise
- MS SQL Server Proficiency
- Power BI Reporting
- Strong Verbal Communication

CERTIFICATIONS AND TRAININGS

- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Fundamentals (DP-900)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure Data Engineer Associate (DP-203)
- Microsoft Certified: Azure
 Fundamentals (AZ-900)

0

WORK EXPERIENCE

Fastenal India Sourcing, IT & Procuremment Pvt Ltd

Dec 2020 - Present

IT Senior Software Engineer

- Working Fastenal's Data Engineering team and BI and Reporting department.
- Designed and developed an Ingestion Automation process to expedite loading of on-prem data sources into Fastenal's data lake.
- Gained expertise in Azure Data Factory, Databricks, Azure DevOps, Terraform, and Spark.
- Coached junior software developers to boost efficiency through guidance on coding standards and performance improvements.
- Developed in-depth reports utilizing Power BI Report Builder.

Sourcebits Technologies Pvt Ltd

Sep 2019 - Dec 2020

BI Developer

- Oversaw the full process of incident resolution through analysis, design, and execution.
- Utilized DDL & DML to create and manage Triggers.
- Developed complex stored procedures to enhance system performance.
- Designed, revised, and enhanced sophisticated queries for data extraction.
- Created comprehensive report detailing proof of concept.
- The aim of the project is to Migrate the data present is different servers to a single server

Understanding Business Specification Documents /Source map documents for creating packages and reports.

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

 Achieved a Spot Award at Fastenal for effectively training new team members and successfully implementing challenging functionality on time

LANGUAGES

- Telugu (Fluent)
- English (Fluent)
- Hindi (Intermediate)

MSC Technologies

Power BI Developer

Sep 2018 - Sep 2019

- Created Relationships at database level and Tabular Model
- Have created calculated fields with DAX expression
- Have created Measures based on business requirement
- experience on creating Power BI Reports with various visualizations
 Used various filters to restrict the data and created Slicers for the user
- Having good experience in Power Query to transform the data within Power Having experience on writing DAX queries to pull data from Tabular Model
- Have done Unit Testing and solved issues, which are getting from End User customers

S.I. Systems Technologies

Nov 2016 – June 2018

BI Developer

- Developed and executed task analysis, design, and implementation.
- Developed SQL stored procedures, triggers, functions with T-SQL.
- Utilized advanced joins and sub-queries to integrate data from various databases.
- Developed batch processing jobs.
- Executed ETL operations to support data loads and transformations.

EDUCATION

Completed B. Tech in bio-informatics, 2011 From Bharath University (Chennai)